<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Visual Crackers 💥</title><link>https://visualcrackers.github.io/showcase/docs/VisualComputing/Visual-Ilusions/</link><description>Recent content on Visual Crackers 💥</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>es-es</language><atom:link href="https://visualcrackers.github.io/showcase/docs/VisualComputing/Visual-Ilusions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intro &amp; Background</title><link>https://visualcrackers.github.io/showcase/docs/VisualComputing/Visual-Ilusions/Intro-background/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://visualcrackers.github.io/showcase/docs/VisualComputing/Visual-Ilusions/Intro-background/</guid><description>Intro &amp;amp; Background # Visual Illusions # Visual illusions are phenomena that make us perceive something that is not present or that distorts our perception of reality. These illusions are produced by the complex interaction between our visual system and our brain.
The brain receives information through the eyes and process it to create a coherent image of the world around us. However, this process is not always perfect and can be fooled by various visual illusions that make us perceive things differently than they really are.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://visualcrackers.github.io/showcase/docs/VisualComputing/Visual-Ilusions/Conclusions-Future-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://visualcrackers.github.io/showcase/docs/VisualComputing/Visual-Ilusions/Conclusions-Future-work/</guid><description>Conclusions # Conclusions # Image processing technology has revolutionized the way we view and interact with digital media. Libraries such as p5.js provide developers with powerful tools to manipulate images and graphics, allowing for creative and interactive applications. One area where image processing technology can make a significant impact is in improving accessibility for people with visual impairments or color blindness.
Recoloring an image is a useful tool for improving image accessibility, as it can help users distinguish between different elements in an image.</description></item></channel></rss>